Mss.B.G784
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, British Museum, Feb. 21, 1850; 9x7-1/2; Adams, Charles Baker, 1814-1853
    Amherst college, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for publications and forwards same.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Feb. 26, 1850; 7x4-1/2; Brown, William, Sir, 1784-1864
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks him to visit. On same sheet is pasted an autograph of Sir William Brown.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], March 5, 1850; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Sundevall, Carl F.
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Asks him to decipher a name and to ask for natural history item.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, March 5, [1850]; 7x4-1/2; Bowman, William, Sir, 1816-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Busk's name is up for the Royal Society.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1850 March 20; Jervis, John
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1850 March 23; Sutherland, Alexander John
  - Letter to John Edw[ard] Gray, March 30, 1850; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 1p. Introduces John A. Lowell.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1850 April ? 19; Tooke, William
  - Letter to the British museum, May 15, 1850; 10x8-3/4; Hoeg
    Bergen, Norway, A.L.S. 1p. Offers natural history objects for sale.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1850 June 8; Phillipps, Thomas, Sir
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], July 9, 1850; 7x4-1/2; Beaumont, Lord
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. Concerning a bill in parliament.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, July 17, 1850; 7x4-1/4; Ellis, Henry, Sir, 1777-1869
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for publication. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, 20 July, 1850; Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, July 20, 1850; Horsfield, Thomas, 1773-1859
    Kew, A.L.S. 2p. Requests testamonial for J.D. Hooker for Botanical Chair at Edinburgh. Mentions Dr. Graham. 1. Edinburgh, University of. 2. Graham, Robert, 1786-1845. 3. Hooker, Joseph Dalton.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, British Museum, Aug. 5, 1850; 4x5-1/4; Ehrenberg, Christian Gottfried, 1795-1876
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Recommends the Drs. Schlagentweit.
  - Letter to John E. Gray, Aug. 23, 1850; 8x5; Fleming, John, 1785-1857
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 4p. Thanks for gift of Mrs. Gray's publication. Concerning friends. Concerning natural history.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1850 August 24; Bank of England.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, London, Sept. 16, 1850; 1/4x5-1/4; Lefevre, Jean Jacques, 1779-1858
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Concerning birds.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1850 December 7; Newton, William John, Sir
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, London, Oct. 8, 1850; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Recluz
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning mollusks.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Oct. 17, 1850; 7x4-1/4; Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks question about conchology.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Oct. 30, 1850; 7x4-1/2; Bowles, William Lisle, 1762-1850
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks if he could see items lately arrived from Ninevah.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Nov. 5, 1850; 8-1/2x5-3/4; Krantz, August
    Bonn, A.L.S. 1p. Offers collections for sale to him.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Nov. 6, 1850; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Holboll
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Sends list of natural history specimens.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Nov. 16, 1850; 7x4-1/2; Bean, William
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks if shells were received from him.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Nov. 19, 1850; 6x3-1/2; Bostock, J. A.
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the hours the museum is open, and apologizes for bring people there when it was closed.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Nov. 24, 1850; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868
    A.L.S. 2p. Sends letter from lady in Jamaica concerning shells. Sir Walter Trevelyan suggested sending the letter to Gray.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Dec. 9, 1850; 6-1/2x4; Schlagintweit-Sakünlünski, Hermann Rudolph Alfred von, 1826-1882
    A.L.S. 2p. Refuses invitation.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1851? Tuesday; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 6, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Acland, Henry Wentworth, 1815-1900
    A.L.S. 3p. Has already received his publication. Sorry to have missed Captain Parry.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, London, Jan. 7, 1851; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Oersted, Hans Christian, 1777-1851
    Copenhagen, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Thanks for publication. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 15, 1851; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Fitton, William Henry, 1780-1861.
    Tumbridge Wells, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning his plates of fossil shells.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, London, Jan. 21, 1851; 7-3/4x5; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. Asks a favor. Concerning wolves.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 23, 1851; 9-3/4x8-1/4; Grateloup, Jean-Pierre Silvestre de, 1782-1862
    Bordeaux, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning mollusks.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 24, 1851; 8-1/2x5; Kröll, Charles
    Mainz, A.L.S. 1p. Asks a favor.
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, 1851 January 26; Pratt, John Tidd
  - Letter to [Samuel Pickworth] Woodward, Jan. 29, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Landrell, J.
    Oxford, A.L.S. 2p. Wishes to sell his collection of snakes.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1851 February 11; Pascoe, Francis Polkinghorne
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Feb. 26, 1851; 10x7-3/4; Bunsen, Robert, 1811-1899
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p. Will forward book to Berlin.
  - Letter to Dr. Kaup, March 11, 1851; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Siebold, Philipp Franz von, 1796-1866
    A.L. 2p. In German.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward gray, 1851 March 11; Roget, Peter Mark, 1779-1869
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, March 18, 1851; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Ellis, Robert
    Blackfriars, L.S. 1p. Answers question. On same sheet is: J. E. G[ray] to [R. Ellis]; March 18, 1851.
  - Letter to [Robert Ellis], March 18, 1851; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
    A.L.S. with initials. 1p. Draft. His question was misunderstood.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 March 29
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, March 31, 1851; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Ball, Robert, 1802-1857
    A.L.S. 1p. Wishes to obtain a portrait of Gray.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, April 14, 1851; 4-1/2x7-1/4; Cocks, W. P.
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwards specimens alive.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 23, 1851; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Grey, Charles, 1804-1870
    A.L.S. 3p. Thanks for publications to the royal library.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, April 25, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Bowring, Edgar A.
    Whitehall, A.L.S. 2p. Cannot accept invitation.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, May 5, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Derby, Edward Smith Stanley, Earl of, 1775-1851
    A.L.S. 3p. and add. Has been ill. Lists plans and hopes for the future.
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, May 27, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Abbott
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 May 27; Wallich, Nathaniel
  - Letter to Mr and Mrs John Edward Gray, 1851 May 28; Northcote, Stafford Henry, Sir
  - Letter to Mr and Mrs Gray, 1851 May 29
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, June, 1851; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Cautley, G. S.
    A.L.S. 3p. Introduces a friend who wishes to see the museum.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, London, June 2, 1851; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Philippi, Rudolfo Amado, 1808-1904
    Carlshutte, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning mollusks.
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, June 2, 1851; 6-1/2x5; Sagra, Ramon de la 1798-1871
    London, A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. In French. Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1851? June 5; Solly, Edward
  - Concerning Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray's publication on mollusks, June 20, 1851; 4x6-1/2; Philippi, Rudolfo Amado, 1808-1904
    A.D.S. 1p. and end. In German.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 27, 1851; 8x5-1/4; Verreaux, F. P.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning birds for the museum.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, July 1, 1851; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Britton, John, 1771-1857
    A.L.S. 2p. Asks for portrait of him.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], July 7, 1851; 3x5; Hoeven, Jan van der, 1802-1868
    Leiden, A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Introduces a friend.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1851 July 11; Mitchell, D.W.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 July 13; Hodgkin, Thomas, 1798-1866
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1851 July 16; Lucy, William
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], July 19, 1851; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Albers, Jean Frédéric Hermann, 1805-1867
    A.L.S. 1p. Sorry he could not accept the invitation.
  - Letter to James (John) Edward Gray, 1851 July 21; Hawkins, Walter
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, July 24, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Bell, John, 1811-1895
    Kensington, A.L.S. 1p. Asks him to dinner to meet friends.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, Aug. 6, 1851; 9-3/4x8; Pfeiffer, Louis Georg Karl, 1805-1877
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Accepts his offer to translate his article. Lists his methods of arranging natural history items.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 August 13; Saunders, W. Wilson, (William Wilson), 1809-1879
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 August 28
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, London, Sept. 1, 1851; 9-1/2x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: John Cassin. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1851 September 4; Van Voorst, John
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Sept. 12, 1851; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Balard, Antoine Jérome, 1802-1876
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. Remembers his visit to the museum with much pleasure. Recommends a friend who comes to London.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, London, Sept. 18, 1851; 8x5-1/4; Nauchet
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning the difficulty of forwarding natural history specimens.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 September 23; Steenstrup, J. Japetus Sm. -- (Johannes Japetus Sm.), -- 1813-1897.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, London, Oct. 1, 1851; 10x7-3/4; Sterling, James H.
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Wishes to know the number of birds in the British museum for the curator of the ANS of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 October 7; Knight, Charles
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Oct. 10, 1851; 10x7-3/4; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning fishes and the exchange of specimens.
  - Letter to John E. Gray, London, Oct. 28, 1851; 9-3/4x9; Sommer, M. C.
    Altona, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Forwards insects as thanks for his courtesies.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Oct. 31, 1851; 11-3/4x8-1/4; Albert Francis Charles Augustus Emmanuel, Prince-Consort of England], 1819-1861.
    L.S. 1p. Forwards token of appreciation for help for making the Exposition a success.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, Nov. 8, 1851; 10x8; Guérin-Méneville, F.E. (Felix Edouard), 1799-1874
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning specimens for the museum.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 November 14; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
    The letter is signed T. Bland and the handwriting was compared with a letter written by Thomas Bland in the Scientist's Collection Call number: 509.L56
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Nov. 17, 1851; 8x5-1/4; Guérin-Méneville, F.E. (Felix Edouard), 1799-1874
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning publication on natural history.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Nov. 18, 1851; 8x5-1/2; Dufrene, G. E.
    A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning natural history. Refers to R. Owen.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1851 November 20; Kellett, Henry, Sir
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Nov. 28, 1851; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Loren, S.
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 3p. Introduces a friend. Concerning mollusks.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Nov. 28, 1851; 6x3-3/4; Loren, S.
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 1p. Sends gift.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1851 December 6; Pasley, Charles William, Sir
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, Dec. 10, 1851; 7-3/4x5-1/4; Geoffroy St. Hilaire, Isidore, 1805-1861
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Concerning certain birds, the aepyornis.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Dec. 15, 1851; 8-1/2x8-1/4; Lubbren, Sorsbie
    Kiel, A.L.S. 1p. Letter hasn't been answered because his correspondent has been severely ill.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Dec. 20, 1851; 8-3/4x6-3/4; Parzudaki, C.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Forwards specimens of natural history to him.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Jan. 15, 1852; 7x4; Jerichau-Baumann, Elizabeth, 1819-1881
    A.L.S. 1p. Accepts invitation. Glad she liked her pictures.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Feb. 14, 1852; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Cailliaud, Frédéric, 1787-1869
    Nantes, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks him to deliver a letter to Mr. Robertson.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, London, Feb. 26, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Fr.Thiersch 1p. and add. In German. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, March 10, 1852; 9x5-1/2; Troschel, Franz Hermann]
    Bonn, A.L.S. 2p. Forwards publication on mollusks.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 10, 1852; 9x7-1/2; Cetto, Baron de
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Delivers diploma.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], April 19, 1852; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Greville, Robert Kaye, 1794-1866
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 3p. Has forwarded material to Mrs. Gray. Asks questions about disposing of shells.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1852 April 27; Pratt, John Tidd
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, May 18, 1852; 10x8-1/2; Copenhagen. K. Danske Videnskabernes Selskab
    Copenhagen, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Forchhammer. 1p. In Danish. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], May 25, 1852; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Griffiths, Amelia W.
    A.L.S. 2p. Is glad she has sold her collection to the museum. Concerning algae.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, June 9, 1852; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Rüppell, Eduard, 1794-1884
    Frankfurt am Main, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Hopes to visit with him in London shortly.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 14, 1852; 10x7; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning Valenciennes and his works. Concerning natural history.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 14, 1852; 10x7; Potteau
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, June 24, 1852; 9x5-1/2; Troschel, Franz Hermann
    Bonn, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In German.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, London, July 6, 1852; 7-1/2x6-1/2; Griffiths, Amelia W.
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning algae.
  - Letter to Jean [sic] Edward Gray, London, July 12, 1852; 9-1/2x8-1/2; Bianconi, John Joseph
    Bologne, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning a friend who is to collect reptiles, etc.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1852 September 23?; Rintoul, Robert Stephen
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, London, Oct. 5, 1852; 10x7-1/2; Plocquet, Hermann
    Stuttgart, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Asks for job at the British museum since he is a first-rate taxidermist.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, Oct. 18, 1852; 9x5-1/2; Rüppell, Eduard, 1794-1884
    Frankfurt am Main, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Zoological society business. Fishes.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1853 February 22; Pasley, Charles William, Sir
  - Letter to John Stokes, Feb. 28, 1853; 6-1/4x4-1/2; St. Davids, C.
    Carmarthen, A.L.S. 1p. Encloses check for school.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1853 May 29; Sowerby, George Brettigham Sr?
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Aug. 12, 1853; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bunsen, Robert, 1811-1899
    A.L.in 3rd. P. 2p. Returns passport and explains rules.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Sept. 29, 1853; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Maury, Matthew Fontaine, 1806-1873
    London, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for presents. Sends chart of the North Atlantic.
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, Oct. 9, 1853; 4-3/4x5-1/2; Bonaparte, Charles Lucien Jules Laurent, Prince de Canino, 1803-1857
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. Introduces his daughter and her husband.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Dec. 4, 1853; 6x4; Fletcher, Eliza Dawson, 1770-1858
    A.L.S. 2p. Has promised her vote elsewhere.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1853 December 4; Alder, Joshua
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, Feb. 6, 1854; 8x5-1/4; Hetzel, Pierre Jules, 1814-1886
    A.L.S.: Stahl. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning a specimen of natural history.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, British Museum, April 5, 1854; 7x4-1/4; Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Thanks for loan of animal for model.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, April 22, 1854; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Andrews, William, 1802-1880
    Dublin, A.L.S. 4p. Introduces Kinahan and asks if any specimens can be sent to Dublin by him.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, May 11, 1854; 7x4-1/2; Fraser, Louis, 1801-1866
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 1p. Leaves for Iagos. Asks that catalogues be left with a friend.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 22, 1854; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Fable, James
    A.L.S. 2p. Has forwarded publication to the King of Portugual and returns his thanks for it.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], July 25, 1854; 7-3/4x5; Holmberg, H.J.
    Helsingfors, A.L.S. 2p. In German.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, November 6, 1854; Nuttall, Thomas, 1786-1859
    Scope and Content note
    Nutgrove, Is prepared to sell his shell collection to Gray. Mentions Conrad, Jay's Catalogue, Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. 1. Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. 2. Conrad, Timothy Abott, 1803-1877. 3. Jay, John Clarkson, 1808-1891. I. [Gray, John Edward], 1800-1875.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, November 6, 1854; Nuttall, Thomas, 1786-1859
    Nutgrove, Abbott, 1803-1877. 1. Jay, John Clarkson, 1808-1891. I. [Gray, John Edward], 1800-1875.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Dec. 18, 1854; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Great Britain. Hydrographic Office.
    Printed L.S.: F.Beaufort. 1p., end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Jan. 3, 1855; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bryson, Alexander, 1802-1869
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards shells for identification.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1855 January 13; Spence, William
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Feb. 21, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Baily, William H.
    A.L.S. 2p. Will call and get specimens of shells.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Feb. 27, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Cole, Henry, Sir, 1808-1882
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for offer.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], April 2, 1855; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Baikie, William Balfour, 1825-1864
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks for an appointment.
  - Letter to "My dear Madam", April 9, 1855; 5-1/2x4-1/2; Carpenter, Philip Pearsall, 1819-1877
    Warrington, A.L.S. 1p. Explains why he did not deliver not in person. Refers to the Gray's.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], April 27, 1855; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bate, Charles Spence, 1819-1889.
    Plymouth, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning crustaca in the British museum.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, May 5, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Buckson, G. B.
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for contribution to Bell's portrait.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1855 May 5; Hearsey, J.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray and Francis Walker, London, May 21, 1855; 7x5-3/4; Fitch, Asa, 1809-1879
    Salem, N.Y., A.L.S. 3p. and add. Introduces Antonio de Lacenda. Concerning his work on insects of New York. Concerning a publication of Say.
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", 3 June 1855; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, June 18, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Dickson, Elizabeth Dalzel, 1793-1862.
    Tripoli, A.L.S. 2p. Introduces her sister, Mrs. Gagliuffi.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, June 18, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Gagliuffi, Dickson, Elizabeth Dalzel, 1793-1862.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Sept. 6, 1855; 8x5-1/4; Anderson, John Henry, 1815-1874
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his note and forwards item.
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, Sept. 12, 1855; 3-3/4x4-1/2; Jaeger, Oskar
    A.L. in 3rd P. 1p. Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Oct. 19, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Brodie, Benjamin Collins, Sir, 1783-1862
    A.L.S. 2p. Asks information.
  - Letter to Mrs. M[aria] E[mma] Gray, London, Nov. 20, 1855; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Pfizer, Marie
    Stuttgart, A.L.S. 4p., add. Introduces her cousin, Gustav Schwab, an American. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Dec. 19, 1855; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Cocks, John
    Devonport, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning algae.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Feb.16, 1856; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Graham, Thomas, 1805-1869
    A.L.S. 1p. Returns pamphlets.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], March 1(?), 1856; 9x5-1/2; Jaeger, Oskar
    Halle, A.L.S. 2p. Recommends a friend who seeks to use the reading room of the museum. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Sir [sic] John Edward Gray, London, Jan. 10, 1856; 10x8-1/2; Jager, George
    Stuttgart, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning the arrangement of natural history specimens in the museum. Refers to Charles Bonaparte's work and wishes to borrow it.
  - Letter to John Edward Grey (Gray), 1856 February 18; Walinsky?, J?
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, March 2, 1856; 9x5-1/2; Wulsten, Clara
    Frankfurt a.d. Oder, A.L.S. 2p. Introduces a friend who wishes to see the museum. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1856 March 21; Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, March 25, 1856; 10x8; Académie des Sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Flourens. 1p. and add. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1856 April 15; Hawkins, Edward
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1856 April 17; Tooke, Thomas
  - Letter to [Mrs. Maria Emma Gray], April 25, 1856; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bowerbank, James Scott, 1797-1877
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], April 28, 1856; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Cayley, A[rthur], 1821-1895
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Will accept invitation.
  - Letter to Mr & Mrs John Edward Gray, 1856 April 28; Loftus, William Kennett?
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1856 July? 31; Smith, Archibald
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1856 September 23; Stenelly?, John
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1856 September 25; Thompson, Thomas Perronet, 1783-1869
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1856 October 9; Thompson, Thomas Perronet, 1783-1869
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1856 November 13; Latham, Robert Gordon, 1812-1888
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Feb. 5, 1857; 9x6; Portugual. British legation
    L. 2p. Will transmit letter to the king, who takes great interest in the British museum.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1857 February 13; Stevens, Samuel
  - Letter to Mr. Watson, Feb. 28, 1857; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
    A.L.S. 3 p., end. Concerns making arrangements to meet.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1857 April 12; Stephans?, J.L.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], April 16, 1857; 5-1/4x4-3/4; Pfeiffer, Ida Reyer, 1797-1858
    A.L.S. 2p. Forwards natural history specimens.
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", 1858?; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to Williams & Norgate, 1858 January 8; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to William & Norgate, 1858 February 6; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to William & Norgate, 1858? February 18; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1858 February 19; Stokes, George Gabriel, Sir
  - Letter to William & Norgate, 1858 March 5; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", 1858 May 22; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to Dr. and Mrs. Gray, May 24, 1858; 3x3-3/4; Jerichau-Baumann, Elizabeth], 1819-1881
  - Letter to G. M. Browne, 1858 December 31; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1859 February 4; Lindley, John, 1799-1865
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1859 March 9; Harvey, William H.(William Henry),1811-1866.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1859 April 18; Murchison, Rodney Impey, Sir
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1859 December 27; Tennent, James Emerson, Sir, 1804-1869
  - Letter to Mrs. John Edward Gray, 1860 June 5; Revy, J. J.
  - Prescription, 1860 June 26; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Mrs. Deros, Sept. 29, 1860; Gray, Maria Emma, 1787-1876
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Feb. 18, 1861; 7x4-1/2; Brodie, Benjamin Collins, Sir, 1783-1862
    L.S. 1p. will send medal when one is struck.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1861 March 28; Harvey, William H.(William Henry),1811-1866.